MARC MOTEN

Garland, TX 75043

Phone: 972-971-3397 | Email: marcmotenii@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/marcmotenii</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/Mamii868</u>

Portfolio: https://mamii868.github.io/React-Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer prepared to learn and develop my skills through experience. I have recently received a certificate in full stack development from Southern Methodist University, acquiring skills in web design, CSS, Javascript, React.js, MySQL, and MongoDB/Apollo. I have especially learned how to work as a team to build different programs in this course, giving me vital experience of working on projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Applications: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, MySQL, React, Apollo

PROJECTS

DeFi101 | Github: https://github.com/Mamii868/Defi-101

Website: https://mamii868.github.io/Defi-101

- This application lets you search different cryptocurrencies, gives an introduction to cryptocurrency, and shows news regarding the specific currency selected
- I created a separate page showing videos to teach about crypto as well as a news portion that updates based on what currency is selected.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Collection Social Share | Github: https://github.com/Mamii868/collection_social_share Website: https://collection_social_share.

- This application is a take on social media for collectors, allowing you to upload pictures of your collections online to show off.
- I was tasked with using MySQL to create a database to store and pull the accounts and collections as well as design the pages.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, NodeJS, Express

App Track | Github: https://github.com/Mamii868/app-track Website: https://powerful-reaches-64620.herokuapp.com

- This application lets users create an account and manage job applications on a job board. The user is prompted with places to fill in information as well as an option to scrape data from LinkedIn about the job posting.
- I created and managed the database and most functions interacting with the information using GraphQL.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, React, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express

EXPERIENCE

Operations Manager

March 2022 - Present Garland, TX

Garland Aquatics

Effectively trained new hires to be CPR and Lifeguard certified

- Successfully maintained a safe aquatic facility as well as addressed any customer issues that arose in a swift manner
- Efficiently trained lifeguards to uphold the safety standards of Garland Aquatics

Secretary

2020 - 2022

Lindstrom Law Firm

Mesquite, TX

- Swiftly provided a faster way of managing clients by using a database to keep track of information within the first few months.
- Assisted in gathering a large list of potential clients and business partners to grow the company's network.
- Successfully managed the new office location to ensure cleanliness and optimal communication with the main office.

Senior Lifeguard

2019 - 2021

Garland Aquatics

Garland, TX

- Properly sanitized the park to maintain cleanliness and quality standards of Garland Aquatics for over 900 customers a day.
- Used critical judgment skills to uphold the standard of safety inside the facility

EDUCATION

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX

April 2021 - October 2021

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

Dallas College, Dallas, TX

2020 - Present

Currently Enrolled